Guide to the Wesley Clair Mitchell Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: [C] Correspondence, (8 Boxes: Boxes 7-14)
  - Burns, Arthur F.
    - 1)
      - [1936 summer?]; a.l.s. 3 p; comments on WCM Harvard Tercentenary Address - intelligence and planning. (Box 7)
      - 1936 Aug 5; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; sends letter from G. Robinson and copy reply (reply encl. 8/3); Harvard Address; Bulletin draft; on letter from L. Currie - offer to Burns. (Box 7)
      - 1936 August [3-6?]; a.l.s. 1 p; on reply on Volkeneau to Robinson. (Box 7)
    - 2)
      - 1936 Aug 6; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; sends draft of Bulletin; on Harvard Tercentenary address draft; MBC progress; long cycle; amplitude measurement. (Box 7)
      - [1936 August9?]; a.l.s. 1 p; on chart construction. (Box 7)
      - 1936 August 11; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 8/8; chart construction; MBC progress; G. Robinson and Volkeneau. (Box 7)
      - [1936 Aug 12?]; a.l.s. 1 p; on long, short and seasonal cycles amplitude measurement; MBC progress. (Box 7)
    - 3)
      - 1936 Aug 19; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 8/17; sends Mills letter on Chapter III. (Box 7)
      - 1936 Aug 24; a.l.s. 1 p; sends revised Bulletin draft, Mills; on Mills letter. (Box 7)
      - 1936 Aug 25: a.l.s. 1 p; sends comments on Bulletin by Bliss and Wolman. (Box 7)
      - 1936 Aug 26; t.l.s. and carbon 1 p; WCM letter; on revised Bulletin, Mills; books as transient goods - with note by Burns. (Box 7)
      - 1936 Aug [26-31?]; a.l.s. 1 p; books classification. (Box 7)
      - 1936,[Aug?]; a.l.s. 1 p; agricultural data - Laubenstein; Bulletin. (Box 7)
      - 1936 [n.d.]; a.l.s. 1 p; railroad and Western Union revenues series. (Box 7)
    - 4)
      - 1937 Jun 14; t.l.s. 1 p; sends tables and charts - foreign railroads, U.S. shoe output. (Box 7)
      - 1937 Jun 20; a.l.s. 3 p; WCM letter; Burns’ classification variance analysis and foreign cycles, duration. (Box 7)
      - 1937 Jun 26; a.l.s. 5 p; reply to 6/20; variance analysis, duration comparisons. (Box 7)
      - [1937 July 9?]; a.l.s. 4 p; German building series - Spiethoff; reference dates and types of series. (Box 7)
      - 1937 Jul 12; a.l.s. 4 p; WCM reply to 7/9; on setting reference dates; foreign series work. (Box 7)
      - [1937 July ?]; a.l.s. 3 p; foreign building and railroad series difficulties; German reference dates. (Box 7)
      - [1937 July or August]; a.l.s. 2 p; reply; foreign building series; long cycles; annual, reference dates. (Box 7)
    - 5)
      - 1941 May 19; t.l.s. 4 p; reply; terminology of dating expansion. (Box 7)
      - 1941 May [?]; a.l.s. 2 p; reference cycle stages and dating terminology; WCM notes. (Box 7)
      - 1941 Oct 13; a.l.s. 4 p; criticisms of NB Reports and suggestions for future. (Box 7)
      - 1947 Jun 10; see W. Carson. (Box 7)
      - [1947 Sept ?]; a.l.s. 1 p; reply; on future work. (Box 7)
    - 6)
      - 1948 [Jun-Aug?]; a.l.s. 1 p; visit plans. (Box 7)
      - 1948 Oct 15; carbon 1 p; to Gunter Reimann; on Reimann’s manuscript. (Box 7)
      - 1948 [n.d.]; a.l.s. 1 p; on title for WHDBC. (Box 7)
      - [n.d.]; a.l.s. 1 p; on Chapter III, Habeler; Bulletin progress; series troubles; table construction (Box 7)
      - [n.d.]; a.l.s. 2 p; conference plans -WCM manuscript. (Box 7)
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray
    - 1913 Oct 28; t.l.s. 1 p; to J.G. Brooks; on proposed WCM professorship. (Box 7)
    - 1922 Mar 7; t.l.s. 1 p; sends Trustees resolution on WCM Columbia reappointment. (Box 7)
    - 1922 Mar 10; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 3/7 (on back of Butler letter 3/7)(by secretary); plans to confer with Woodbridge and McBain. (Box 7)
    - 1937 .May 29; carbon 1 p; WCM reply; on operation recovery. (Box 7)
    - 1944 Apr 13; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; Columbia resignation. (Box 7)
  - Calkins, Gary N.
    - 1936 Dec 28; t.l.s. 1 p; requests recommendation of W. Ripley for Century Club; Bruere. (Box 7)
    - 1936 Dec 31; carbon 1 p; WCM reply; acknowledgement. (Box 7)
  - Calvert, G. N.
    - 1946 December23 t.l.s. 1 p; requests NB Reports - wants to form similar Australia-New Zealand bureau. (Box 7)
  - Campbell, Wallace J.
    - 1937 Apr 9; mimeograph 1 p; requests subscription to Consumers’ Cooperation; sends bibliography (encl. 1 p) (Box 7)
  - Capen, S.V.
    - 1947 Jul 10; t.l.s. 1 p; sends resolution on WCM honorium for Buffalo seminars. (Box 7)
    - 1947 Oct 21; t.l.s. 1 p; sends trustee resolution on WCM Resignation. (Box 7)
  - Carbert, Leslie E.
    - 1947 Mar 17; t.l.s. 1 p; Columbia Graduate Economics Club wants WCM to speak. (Box 7)
  - Carlile, William Warrand
    - 1912 Mar 14; a.l.s. 1 p; sends galley proof of own review of Jevons' Theory of Political Economy (encl. 1 p) (Box 7)
  - Carman, Harry J.
    - 1947 Jan 28; t.l.s. 1 p; on Dorfman's criticism of Schlesinger's Age of Jackson. (Box 7)
  - Carson, William J.
    - 1947 Jun 6; see M. Houston. (Box 7)
    - 1947 Jun 10; copy 1 p; to A.Burns; sends copy letter from M. Houston (6/l0) (American Book Publishers' Council) (Box 7)
    - 1947 Jun 12; t.l.s. 1 p; reports on C.R. Noyes’ health. (Box 7)
    - 1947 Jul 21; see G. Tagliacarne. (Box 7)
    - 1947 Jul 25; carbon sip; sends copy letter from G. Tagliacarne (see Tagliacarne 7/21), comments. (Box 7)
    - 1947 Aug 18; carbon sip; sends copy letter and report from I. Marchisio (see Marchisio 8/14) (Box 7)
    - 1947 Aug 27; t.l.s. 1 p; sends copy Jacoby and Saulneer's Business Finance and Banking; Neil. (Box 7)
    - 1947 Dec 26; carbon sip; sends letter from P.W. Martin to Mills (see Martin 11/7) (Box 7)
  - Cates, Dudley
    - 1948 Jun 2; t.l.s. 1 p; lunch plans. (Box 7)
  - Cattell, J. McKean
    - 1936 Oct 10; t.l.s, 1 p; requests permission to publish WCM Harvard Tercentenary address in Scientific Monthly. (Box 7)
    - 1936 Oct 13; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 10/10 grants permission. (Box 7)
  - Chamberlain, Joseph P. (Box 8)
    - 1948 Apr 7; t.l.s. 1 p; requests money for Survey Associates; note by WCM (Box 8)
  - Chapin, Stuart
    - 1936 Nov 27; t.l.s. 2 p; questions on SSRC conferences. (Box 8)
  - Chase, Stuart
    - 1947 Mar 13; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to 3/7; thanks for questionnaire answers. (Box 8)
    - 1948 May 4; t.l.s. 1 p; thanks for help on Proper Study of Mankind; D. Young, C. Pollard, C. Canfield; sends chapter outline (encl. l p) (Box 8)
  - Chawner, Lowell T.
    - 1938 May 21; t.l.s. 1 p; sends Department of Commerce bulletin "Construction Activity in the United States, 1915-37" (encl.) (Box 8)
  - Christian, Hans J.
    - 1947 May 13; a.l.s. 3 p; wants WCM interview; own past work - sends biography (encl. 2 p) (Box 8)
    - 1947 May 23; a.l.s. 1 p; interview plans. (Box 8)
  - Clark, John Bates
    - 1915 Feb 8; t.l.s. 1 p; J. B. Clark biographical plan. (Box 8)
  - Clark, John Maurice
    - 1)
      - 1915 Jan 24; a.l.s. 7 p; on J.B. Clark, cycles and dividend manipulation; BC (13) equilibrium and cumulative forces; acceleration principle; limits of credit; industrial and financial cycle elements. (Box 8)
      - [1915], Mar 20; a.l.s. 2 p; "ratio of exchange" controversy with B.M. Anderson. (Box 8)
      - 1915 Mar 28; a.l.s. 2 p; Anderson controversy. (Box 8)
      - 1922 Dec 4; a.l.s. 2 p; own and WCM papers for AEA. (Box 8)
      - 1922 Dec 7; carbon 1 p; WCM reply. (Box 8)
    - 2)
      - 1926 Apr 8; a.l.s. 1 p; on own Colombia appointment; self and JBC. (Box 8)
      - 1927 Apr 21: a.l.s. 2 p; self and WCM- induction and behaviorism; human nature and economics; agencies and functions as approaches the business enterprise. (Box 8)
      - 1928 Aug 9; copy [incomplete] 12 p; WCM reply; autobiographical letter [see Stuart Rice 2/5 - 2/12/1929 and R. Lynd 2/9/29] (Box 8)
      - 1929 Feb 11; t.l. and' carbon 11 & 11 p; WCM letter; revised version (by WCM) of letter to Clark 8/9/23 (for Rice) (Box 8)
      - 1936 December11 carbon 1 p; WCM letter: on Becker and Clark's seminar. (Box 8)
    - 3)
      - 1937 May 22; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; conference on Methods in Philosophy and the Sciences; Kallen. (Box 8)
      - 1933 Aug 9; a.l.s. 1 p; on own coming address "Monopolistic Tendencies" for Academy of Political Science, program encl. (1 p.) (Box 8)
      - 1941 Oct 24; a.l.s. 1 p; OPA and previous experience; self and basing point problems. (Box 8)
      - 1944 Jan 13; t.l.s. 1 p; methods in social sciences and limitations classical and statistical. (Box 8)
      - 1944 Jan 19; carbon 2 p; WCM reply to 1/13; methods - statistics, NB. (Box 8)
      - 1948 May 14; t.l.s. 2 p; reply; on own book. (Box 8)
      - 1948 May 22; a.l.s. 1 p; reply to 5/16; on coming Amherst lectures [Guideposts], H. Wallace; Economics as a science and economic models. (Box 8)
  - Clawson, Joseph
    - 1947 Aug 17; t.l.s. 1 p; on WCM's "Facts and values in economics"; psychological studies; C. Noyes; own background. (Box 8)
  - Clay, Henry
    - 1921 Nov 7; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; sends copy BC (13); M. Rutherford; NB and Conference on Unemployment study. (Box 8)
    - 1921 Nov 18; a.l.s. 2 p; reply to 11/7; on NB methods - Stewart, Wolman; self at Oxford; WCM Post articles. (Box 8)
    - 1923 May 30; a.l.s. 2 p; planned survey of postwar depression - requests WCM paper; British economics; W. Berridge, Hamilton, Wolman, Stewart. (Box 8)
    - 1924 Oct 31; a.l.s. 2 p; sends Marsh's article on business cycles; Carroll, Schaltner, Hamilton. (Box 8)
    - 1924 Nov 11; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 10/31 EC (27) progress; AEA work. (Box 8)
  - Clough, Shepard B.
    - 1944 Oct 4; t.l.s. 1 p; recommends Chlepner's Belgian banking and banking theory. (Box 8)
  - Coats, R. H.
    - 1936 Dec 29; t.l.s. 1 p; requests copy WCM’s Harvard Tercentenary paper, similar Canadian suggestion (sends economic Council Bill-not encl.) (Box 8)
    - 1937 Jan 5; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 12/23 requests Hudson Bay lynx skin sales series. (Box 8)
  - Cochrane, James Sullivan
    - 1937 Sep 12; t.l.s. 2 p; sends copy own "Super-Capitalism" (encl. 28 p); offers copy own "Laboratory Economics"; WCM note. (Box 8)
    - 1937 Oct 8; see L. Sloan. (Box 8)
    - 1937 Oct 11; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 9/12; on Cochrane’s paper - accumulation of working capital and unemployment; J. Angell’s Behavior of Money. (Box 8)
    - 1937 Nov 1; t.l.s. 2 p; reply to 10/11j economic concepts and own monetary views; sends E. Sloan letter (see Sloan 10/8) (Box 8)
    - 1937 Nov 3; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 11/1; statistics and theory; meeting plans. (Box 8)
    - 1933 Apr 29: a.l.s. 2 p; sends copy own "Consumer Money Supply" (encl. 9 p); meeting plans. (Box 8)
  - Collins, John
    - 1933 Jul 15; t.l.s. 1 p; business cycle causes - underconsumption. (Box 8)
    - 1936 Jul 23; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 7/13; underconsumption; own work and business cycle theory. (Box 8)
  - Commons, John R.
    - 1)
      - 1921 Dec 20; t.l.s. 1 p; on NB study of national income. (Box 8)
      - 1922 Jan 4; t.l.s. 1 p; sends copy "Correlation of Law and Economics" (not encl.) and chapter of revision of valuation theories (not encl.) (Box 8)
      - 1922 Oct 50; t.l.s. 1 p; sends manuscript of revised chapters on law and value theory; working on wage theory and Veblen. (Box 8)
      - 1922 Nov 9; carbon, a.l. 1 p; WCM reply to 10/50 (on back 10/50); on Commons manuscript. (Box 8)
      - 1923 Mar 29; carbon 2 p; WCM letter; on Reasonable Value; self and history of money economy. (Box 8)
      - 1923 Apr 9; t.l.s. 1 p; Reasonable Value manuscript - sends chapter on Cassel - price determination and statistical usability (not encl.) (Box 8)
      - 1923 Apr 18; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 4/9 (oh back 10/30). (Box 8)
      - 1923 Aug 2; t.l.s. 2 p; asks WCM to be economists for four states in Pittsburgh Plus case. (Box 8)
    - 2)
      - 1924 Jul 10; t.l.s. 1 p; thanks for WCM's "Commons and the legal foundations of capitalism"; Pittsburg Plus; Monetary Association Strong, A. Young, Persons, Rovensky, Catchings, Fisher; plans WCM aid in persuading Cassel and Keynes. (Box 8)
      - 1937 Apr 30; a.l.s. 2 p; thanks for BASI.:; attack on L. Robbins; sends Investigation Economics chapters. (Box 8)
      - 1937 May 7; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 4/30: Investigational Economics; Commons' Institutional Economics and WCM students. (Box 8)
      - 1937 May 29; a.l.s. 1 p; sends chapters; Robbins criticism. (Box 8)
      - 1957 Jun 2; carbon 1 p: WCM’s reply to 5/29; acknowledgement. (Box 8)
    - 3)
      - 1940 Apr 16; a.l.s. 2 p; work on Investigational Economics; Fisher and memorandum to Congress on price stability - own and WCM attitudes; photograph of self encl. (Box 8)
      - 1940 Apr 25; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 4/16; Fisher plan; thanks for "Twentieth Century Economics". (Box 8)
      - 1941 Jun 10: a.l.s. 2 p; wants Mills’ Prices in Recession and Recovery; Investigational Economics progress - Fisher, Graham, Snyder. (Box 8)
      - 1941 Jul 2; a.l.s. 2 p; Investigational Economics progress " collective action cycles"; Mills. (Box 8)
  - Conant, James B.
    - 1935 Feb 5; t.l.s. 3 p; invitation to attend Harvard Tercentenary Conference. (Box 8)
  - Copeland, D.B.
    - 1937 Jun 29; t.l.s. 1 p; wants NB job for J. Polglaze; C. Clark. (Box 8)
  - Copeland, Edith Ayres
    - 1927 July 20; t.l.s. 2 p; requests essay for volume honoring University of Chicago's Department of Philosophy - Tufts, Mead, Moore, Ames. (Box 8)
  - Copeland, Morris A.
    - 1947 Apr 215 a.l.s. 1 p: thanks for letter to English. (Box 8)
  - Courtney, Philip
    - 1948 Jan 7; t.l.s. 1 p; wants copy Tugwell's Trend of Economics. (Box 8)
  - Cox, Richard T.
    - 1941 Dec 21; a.l.s. 5 p; criticisms of WCM paper [Economic Resources and Their Employment?] - majority and individual rights. (Box 8)
  - Craig, Jim
    - 1948 Mar 2; t.l.s. 2 p; queries on WCM and University of Chicago graduates (for business); Kneehaus, Anderson, Emick. (Box 8)
  - Crane, Robert T.
    - 1)
      - 1934 Dec 17; t.l. 1 p; birthday dinner message (Social Science Research Council). (Box 8)
      - 1936 Jul 26; carbon 2 p; Rockefeller Foundation grants - Chester, Webbink, MacNeil (SSRC). (Box 8)
      - 1936 Oct 5; t.l.s. 1 p; invites WCM on committee to Review Council Policy - Ford; May, Schlesinger, Ogburn, Furniss, Redfield, Rogers. (Box 8)
      - 1936 Oct 7; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 10/5; consents to serve. (Box 8)
      - 1936 Nov 16; t.l.s. 1 p; on Committee to Review plans. (Box 8)
      - 1936 Dec 9; t.l.s. 1 p; sends memorandum for Social Security committee (encl. 1 p). (Box 8)
    - 2)
      - 1937 Apr 20; t.l.s. 1 p; thanks for BASM copy. (Box 8)
      - 1937 Jul 26; t.l.s. 2 p; Committee to Review - May; Wirth report. (Box 8)
      - 1937 Aug 21; a.l.s. 1 p; on Shryock; Executive Committee meeting. (Box 8)
      - 1937 Oct 11; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; WCM release from Social Security committee. (Box 8)
      - 1939 Oct 30; t.l.s. 2 p; on manuscript of WCM "Public Relations of Science". (Box 8)
  - Crick, W.F.
    - 1935 Nov 15; t.l.s. 3 p; reply to 11/4 letter by WCM to C.J. Smit; English Interest rates. (Box 8)
    - 1935 Nov 25; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 11/15 Crick's (Midland Bank) book plans; requests permission to quote on interest rates. (Box 8)
    - 1935 Dec 6; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to 11/25 grants permission. (Box 8)
  - Croke [?] W.M.
    - 1947 Dec 22; t.l.s. 1 p; change of address acknowledgement. (Box 8)
  - Crum, W.L.
    - 1936 Oct 20; t.l.s. 1 p; to Miss Anderson; memorandum on WCM and Burns' Bulletin on 1921-33 cycles, major and business cycles. (Box 8)
    - 1936 Oct 21; carbon 2 p; WCM reply to 10/20. (Box 8)
  - Cummings, John
    - 1923 Oct 11; carbon 1 p; WCM reply; on government service. (Box 8)
  - D., R.B.
    - 1909 Jul 15; postcard a.l.s. 1 p; personal news. (Box 8)
  - Daggert, Stuart
    - 1936 Oct 28; t.l.s. 1 p; retirement presentation for Plehn and H. Hatfield (University of California); WCM note on E.V. Gay, Jr. (Box 8)
    - 1936 Nov 6; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 10/28 sends Hatfield and Plehn letters; Gay and Seligman. (Box 8)
  - Daniels, John
    - 1948 Jul 3; t.l.s. 2 p: sends copy own "Towards Industrial Democracy" (encl. 1 p) and J.M. Clark's "Industry and the Worker" (encl. 1 p); requests WCM article. (Box 8)
    - 1948 Jul 20; a.l.s. 2 p; reply; WCM and own labor-management partnership plan. (Box 8)
    - 1948 August9; a.l.s. 1 p; sends copy own "Way to Industrial Peace". (Box 8)
  - Davenport, H. J.
    - 1908 Jun 7; t.l.s. 1 p; WCM letter; own review of Davenport's book; Davenport and Clark, Fetter, Carver, and Fisher; criticism of approach. (Box 8)
    - 1908 [n.d.]; t.l.s. 1 p; reply to 6/7 WCM review; (University of Chicago); Hoxie. (Box 8)
    - [1908 ?]; a.l.s. 1 p; (University of Missouri); sends manuscript [?] (not encl.). (Box 8)
    - 1927 Mar 14; carbon s 2 p; to W. Stewart; King's estimate. of national income, [n.d.]; t.l.s. 1 p; (Standard Statistics Co.); Toronto trip plans. (Box 8)
  - Davis, H. S.
    - 1941 Nov 24; copy 2 p; to Bezanson; on industry studies; Black, J. Dean. (Box 8)
    - 1946 Oct 31; t.l. 1 p; reply to 10/28 sends copy own statement on industry study of economic progress (not encl.) (Box 8)
    - 1927 Mar 31; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 3/14; defends King's estimate. (Box 8)
    - 1946 Nov 26; t.l.s. 1 p; University of Pennsylvania Industrial Research Dept. anniversary celebration plans; H. Clay; program encl. (1 p). (Box 8)
    - 1947 Jan 6; t.l.s. 1 p; WC-A Research Department paper plans; meeting plans. (Box 8)
  - Davis, Joseph S.
    - 1936 Apr 6; see W. Persons. (Box 8)
    - 1936 Aug 11; t.l.s. 1 p; asks HCIA to participate American Farm Economic Association meeting; sends program (encl. 1 p) (Box 8)
    - 1936 Aug 19; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 8/11; recommends B. Ruml as National Resources Committee representative. (Box 8)
    - 1956 Sep 1; t.l.s. 1 p; repeats request. (Box 8)
  - Davis, Malcolm ?
    - 1925 Aug 50; a.l.s. 2 p; asks advice on courses of study. (Box 8)
    - 1951 Jul 7; carbon sip; to E. Gay; Yale University Press and Council on Foreign Relations; sends memorandum (encl. 2 p). (Box 8)
  - Davis, Watson
    - 1959 Nov 28; t.l.s. 1 p; wants WCM to give AAAS address on radio, plans. (Box 8)
    - 1959 Dec 21; t.l.s. 1 p; sends AAAS address script (encl 6 p) (Box 8)
  - Day, Edmund E.
    - 1922 Mar 28; t.l.s. 1 p; University of Michigan plans - Wolman, Stewart, Tryon, Edie. (Box 8)
    - 1925 way 17; t.l.s. 1 p; WCM chapter in Edie’s Stabilization of Business - requests comment on consumer resistance. (Box 8)
    - 1925 May 21; carbon 1 p;(on back 5/17); WCM reply to 5/17; consumer resistance and cycle. (Box 8)
  - Deeds, Allan K.
    - 1947 Feb 15; t.l.s. 1 p; E. Goebel wants German translation of BC; self and Fisher's 100% reserve plan. (Box 8)
  - de Lima, Agnes
    - 1948 May 5; t.l.s. 1 p; requests WCM photograph for New School publicity. (Box 8)
  - Dennison, Henry S.
    - 1)
      - 1921 Oct 18; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; War Industries Board Bulletin on price changes. (Box 8)
      - 1921 Nov 9; t.l.s. 1 p; sends price chart (not encl.) (Box 8)
      - 1921 Nov 14; carbon 1 p; (on back 11/9); WCM reply to 11/9; post Civil War price series and present. (Box 8)
      - 1921 Nov 19; t.l.s. 2 p; secular price movement and. productive capacity. (Box 8)
      - 1921 Nov 22; carbon 1 p; (on back 11/19); WCM reply to 11/19 secular price falls; Sombart. (Box 8)
      - 1921 Dec 22; t.l.s. 2 p; cycles and relative production of essential and non-essential goods. (Box 8)
      - 1921 Dec 24; carbon 1 p; (on back 12/24); WCM reply to 12/22 consumer strikes and crises - Aftalion. (Box 8)
    - 2)
      - 1922 Jan 5; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; thanks for Rolling's notes. (Box 8)
      - 1922 Jan 7; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; NB to study supply and price fluctuation relationships; Unemployment Conference study plans. (Box 8)
      - 1922 Aug 12; t.l.s. 3 p; Post Office cost study - wants WCM, T.S. Adams, Day, and Sterritt to examine figures. (Box 8)
    - 3)
      - 1924 Feb 5; carbon 2 p; WCM letter; suggestions on Harvard Economic Service. (Box 8)
      - 1924 Mar 3; t.l.s. 1 p; suggests want ads as unemployment indicator - Berridge. (Box 8)
      - 1926 Oct 4; carbon 2 p; WCM letter; inventory fluctuations and consumption; Business Annals, BC (27) progress. (Box 8)
      - 1927 May 26; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; analysis of prosperity and the coming year - "mild recession" in 1923 or 1929. (Box 8)
      - 1937 Jun 4; copy 1 p; to McGraw-Hill; praises BASM, Roosevelt's brain trust; Weiser and state action. (Box 8)
  - Dewey, Davis R.
    - 1911 Jan 7; t.l.s. 1 p; criticism of Howard and Johnson in WCM review of Money and Banking. (Box 8)
    - 1913 Oct 22; t.l.s. 1 p; sends C. Jackson's Six Industrial Crises for review. (Box 8)
    - 1914 Jan 12; t.l.s. 1 p; requests review of Davenport's Economics of Enterprise. (Box 8)
    - 1914 Jul 25; t.l.s. 1 p; requests comment on Rubinow's "Recent Trend of True Wages". (Box 8)
  - Dewey, Edward R.
    - 1946 Sep 24; t.l.s. 1 p; sends galley proof of own cycles for criticism. (Box 8)
  - Dewey, John
    - [1934] Feb 9; a.l.s. 2 p; Kraus and Civil Liberties Union. (Box 8)
    - 1934 Feb 14; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 2/9. (Box 8)
    - 1934 Dec 5; a.l.s. 2 p; birthday dinner refusal; praises WCM. (Box 8)
    - 1934 Dec 7; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 12/5; praises Dewey. (Box 8)
  - Diehl, Karl
    - 1927 Oct 27; carbon [?] 1 p; (in German). (Box 8)
  - Dormer, Otto
    - [1947 Dec ?]; a.l.s. 2 p; thanks for aid; Georgetown appointment. (Box 8)
  - Donovan, W.J.
    - [1943 March?]; mimeographed 1 p; knowledge integration project, fund appeal; description enclosed (3 p) (co-signers: A. Ruggles, E. Sinnott, S. Arnold, W.T. Mitchell, M. Groves, G. Emerson, N. Rockefeller) (Box 8)
  - Dorfman, Joseph
    - 1)
      - 1936 May 17; a.l.s. 2 p; BASM preparation. (Box 8)
      - 1936 May 50; a.l.s. 1 ?; BASM preparation. (Box 8)
      - 1936 Jul 15; a.l.s. 1 p; BASM preparation; own Economic Mind in American Civilization progress. (Box 8)
      - 1936 Jul 23; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 7/15; BASH; Harvard Tercentenary address progress. (Box 8)
      - 1936 Aug 25; a.l.s. 1 p; BASM - Harvard Tercentenary address publication. (Box 8)
      - 1936 Aug 28; carbon 1 p; WCM reply to 8/25. (Box 8)
    - 2)
      - 1956 Sep 1;; BASM and Harvard tercentenary address; H. Stuart. (Box 8)
      - 1956 Nov 30; a.l.s. 1 p; BASM - title; contents list encl. (2 p). (Box 8)
      - 1956 Dec 11; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; BASM presentation list. (Box 8)
      - [1936 ?]; a.l.s. 1 p; BASM preparation. (Box 8)
    - 3)
      - 1937 Jan 12; carbon 1 p; WCM letter; sends BASM presentation list (encl. lp.) (Box 8)
      - 1937 Mar 15; a.l.s. 1 p; BASM publication. (Box 8)
      - 1937 May 19; a.l.s. 1 p; sends copy prospective Tugwell review of BASM. (Box 8)
      - 1937 May 20; carbon 1 p; lid reply to 5/19; on Tugwell review. (Box 8)
      - 1937 Jun 8; a.l.s. 1 p; sends letter from H. Dennison on BASM (see Dennison, 6/4); thinking of doing biography of WCM. (Box 8)
    - 4)
      - [1939 ?]; a.l.s. 3 p; on WCM address manuscript - Newton, Franklin, science and social needs and reforms. (Box 8)
      - 1942 Mar 4; a.l.s. 1 p; sends English parliamentary debate (1753) on census and emigration (encl. 4 p). (Box 8)
      - 1945 Jan 5; a.l.s. 1 p; sends "Note on Parrington's Historical Method" (encl. 8 p); WMC and own manuscript. (Box 8)
      - 1946 Jan 1; hol 1 p; J.S. Mill and debt repudiation. (Box 8)
      - 1946 Dec 28; see V. Mund. (Box 8)
      - 1947 Jan 3: a.l.s. 1 p; sends letter from V. Mund (see Mund 12/28/46) (Box 8)
      - 1947 Feb 19; a.l.s, 1 p; own Veblen chapter; WCM comments. (Box 8)
      - 1947 Mar 25; a.l.s. 1 p; sends chapter on WCM for suggestions, A.Burns. (Box 8)
    - 5)
      - [n.d.] a.l.s. 1 p; (on enclosure); sends W. Johnson quotation on McCulloch (1837) (Box 8)